friendrise.com 2012-01-27

# Friendrise :: Legal :: Privacy Policy

PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy is applicable to all products and services, the owner of Friendrise and the users of Friendrise. It applies to all the information and data collected by us for your use of Friendrise and the inbound services of this website.

1) TERMS AND INTERPRETATION:

In the policy, the following terms refers to their specific meaning:

  * “ACCOUNT”: This refers to collection of personal information, payments, and credentials used by the users to access the services of Friendrise and for all the communications done.
  * “CONTENT”: This refers to any text, images, files, videos, graphics, audios, forums, blogs, comments, or any other data and any form of information available on Friendrise for the usage or can be seen to the members and the visitors.
  * “COOKIE”: This refers to the text file which is placed in the computer of visitors when they click on some parts of Friendrise, just to find out their visiting Friendrise to our website. This helps us to study the visiting habits of people to our website.
  * “DATA”: This refers to all the personal and non-personal information provided by you to the website which is not just restricted to the account information.
  * “FRIENDRISE/friendrise”: Friendrise refers to the website and its owners.
  * “Services/services”: This refers to all the online services provided by Friendrise owners in form of interaction facility, tools, service, information and data offered to users now and in future.
  * “SYSTEM”: This refers to the communication set up made available by Friendrise to the users for communication, which includes but is not limited to, web-based e-mails, live chats, message boards, facilities and e-mail links or any other links, now and in future.
  * “USER/USERS”: This refers to the third party connected to Friendrise and who is not employed by Friendrise and is not acting in any course of employment of Friendrise.
  * “WEBSITE”: This refers to current website Friendrise and all its sub-domains[support@friendrise.com until excluded is provided]

2) WEBSITES AND SERVICES OF THIRD PARTY:

Friendrise can hire the services of third party anytime, which may include but is not restricted to data collection, advertising, marketing, payment collection. The third party providers have access to the personal information only upto extend of the service provided by them to Friendrise. Any other usage is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, any kind of Data that is processed by third parties must be processed within the terms of this Policy and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

3) USAGE OF DATA BY FRIENDRISE:

  * Any of the personal data submitted by you will be retained by Friendrise as long as you are a part of our website and the data provided to us by any communication tool will be retained for long period.
  * Unless Friendrise is obliged or permitted by law to do so, and subject to Clause 4, your Data will not be disclosed to third parties.
  * All your personal Data will be stored securely in accordance with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998. For more details on security, see clause 9 given below.
  * The above data collected can be used by us anytime or from time to time to provide you with the best of services possible. Specifically, Data will be used for the following reasons: 
    * Internal record maintenance
    * Changes and improving the services and products offered
    * Sending the promotional offers that may interest you through mails
    * For the market research purpose through E-mail or telephonic conversation to provide customized Friendrise services.

4) RIGHT TO WITHHOLD INFORMATION BY YOU

You can access some services of Friendrise without providing any kind of information except you account related information. You may also restrict the cookies storage. Refer [clause 10] for more information.

5) TRANSFER OF BUSINESS OWNERSHIP AND CONTROL

Friendrise anytime can expand or sell some part or whole of their business. The information provided by you would be transferred in such case which is relevant for the sold business and transaction. Under this policy, the party buying the rights can access your information.  
The user shall not be informed or asked by Friendrise before transferring information in such setup.

6) ACCESS TO YOUR DATA AND CONTROL

When you will provide the data you will be given right to restrict the use of that data by us.

7) RIGHT TO ACCESS YOUR OWN DATA

  * You have the access to change the data provided by you at anytime. The change can be at any given time and the marketing preferences will be changed with the change in your data.
  * You can also have the right to ask the personal copy of the data provided at any time by paying a small administrative fee.

8) SECURITY ASPECT

Security of the data is most important part of Friendrise responsibility and to safeguard this your data is put in suitable places which go through physical, managerial and electronic procedure.

9\. OPTING OUT OPTION

You have the right to opt out of any information provided by Friendrise at any given time.

If you wish not to receive any notification, then you can remove the option from your setting page.

Deleting your account from the settings page will terminate all contacts.

You can also contact us through support page or contact us option to end all the contacts.

10) COOKIES

  * Friendrise have right to store the cookies on your computer.
  * A Cookie is a small file that resides on your computer’s hard drive and often contains an anonymous unique identifier and is only Friendrise can access it as it has placed it there, not any other sites.
  * When you delete the cookies you might loose some information which allows you to access Friendrise quickly.
  * The acceptance or restriction can be done by you for the cookies. Generally it is automatically accepted. For further details please consult the help menu in your browser. Disabling Cookies may prevent you from using the full range of Services available on Friendrise.

11) COLLECTED DATA

Without any kind of limitation or restriction, following data can be collected:

  * Complete name
  * Birth date, month and year
  * Gender
  * Complete contact information like e-mail address, telephone numbers and even the address.
  * Cookie information[see clause-10]
  * Financial information such as the history of your purchases.
  * IP address which is automatically collected.
  * Web browser type and the version which will be automatically collected.
  * Operating system used which also will be automatically collected.
  * The URLS automatically collected which are related to the activities on Friendrise, the referring sites and site you exit to.
  * The information provided by you related to the twitter account through Twitter API and your express permission.
  * The information provided by you related to the FACEBOOK account through FACEBOOK API and your express permission.
  * The information provided by you related to the YOUTUBE account through YOUTUBE API and your express permission.
  * Complete website information.
  * Information and data related to the online connections made by you through Friendrise.

12) CHANGES IN THE POLICY

Friendrise have the complete right to alter the above privacy policy at any given time or as required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on Friendrise and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the Policy on your first use of Friendrise following the alterations.
